Hey English learners, welcome to this A2
English listening practice video. I hope
you're doing well and that you're ready
to practice your listening
comprehension. And in today's video, I'm
going to talk about some unique things
in the US, some things that might be
particular to the US or maybe they're
more common here. So, I'm sure you'll
enjoy this video. And I also want to
remind you that if you need my help to
improve your pronunciation,
for example, if you can't really
distinguish between the words bus and
boss, if you need help with those kinds
of things, make sure to click on the
link below to sign up for my membership
so you can get my training. All right,
let me sit down and we'll get started.
Okay, let me talk about some unique
things here in the US. Uh, first of all,
one of the things that you will notice
when you come here is that there's a lot
of space. So, what do I mean when I say
this? Well, uh, a good example is
streets here, roads, highways. You'll
notice that the lanes are usually pretty
wide. There's a lot of space. Even just
the number of lanes. Oftent times on
freeways or on other streets, there are
many lanes. There's more space. Uh they
are wider. Um, even in parking lots,
usually we have big parking lots at
grocery stores and uh other types of
malls and things like that. And parking
is typically free uh in these types of
parking lots, which is nice. But there's
a lot of space when it comes to roads
and parking lots. Uh, also houses,
right? houses tend to be a little bigger
here than in uh other countries maybe.
Uh there are bigger yards uh like
there's more space outside the house,
behind the house, in front of the house.
Um so there's more space there. Uh
oftent times uh each member each person
who lives in that house uh they have
more personal space. Uh it's less common
in the US for children to share bedrooms
with other siblings. Uh in other
countries that's super common. In the US
it's less common. oftentimes each kid
has their own bedroom. So, you see what
I'm saying? There's a lot of space here.
People really like their space. Um, you
can see it when you look at the houses
here, the yards, the streets, all of
that. There's a lot of space for people
here. Um, another thing that I wanted to
mention is that the US has a very strong
state identity in each state. Uh, the US
has 50 states and each state has an
identity that's unique from other states
and oftent times uh there's pride like
people are proud of their state. Um,
this I think is bigger in the US than in
other countries. In other countries
there are fewer distinctions
between states. Um, maybe people think
more about cities uh rather than states,
but in the US states have a very strong
identity. Um, not only that, but they
also have different laws.
So, some things are legal in some
states, but illegal in other states.
That's really important to know, right?
Um, the atmosphere is different, the
culture is different in different
states. Uh I live in California and it's
very different here uh from other states
in the US. So we have a very strong
state identity in each state and a lot
of distinctions and differences between
different states, different laws. So
this is uh something that is a little
unique because I think that in most
other countries uh states don't have as
much uh power. They can't make uh many
different laws that are different from
other states. Uh people might not pay as
much attention to uh states and
distinctions. So, I think it's something
that exists more here in the US than uh
in other countries. Maybe I'm wrong, but
it's what I've noticed.
Another uh unique thing in the US is the
sports. Um in the US, we don't have one
dominant sport. Uh but in most
countries, this is the case. Usually,
it's soccer. uh like soccer is by far
the most popular sport and the other
sports are down here. In the US, we
don't have this. Uh American football is
the most popular sport that people
watch, but it's not the dominant sport.
There are a lot of other sports that
many people watch like basketball, like
baseball, even hockey,
soccer is becoming a little more
popular. We don't have one dominant
sport. And it's funny because uh this
year is a World Cup year. And often when
Americans watch the World Cup, uh, they
have to learn some of the rules of
soccer. Um, because soccer is not the
dominant sport here like it is in other
countries. Uh I can remember watching
the World Cup here and uh the
commentators
had to explain a couple of the rules
like things that were not allowed.
People here don't know what offsides uh
means. So uh it just shows that soccer
is not our dominant sport. So that's
kind of unique here. And one other um
unique thing in the US is the incredible
amount of variety here. Uh there are
tons of different products for example
that you can buy in the US. you see many
many options and a lot of people like to
come here to go shopping because of all
of the variety.
And for example, uh my wife's family,
they often ask us to buy specific things
here, uh and take them to Mexico when we
visit them, for example, because it's a
lot easier to find those products here.
We have a lot of variety. uh even online
shopping. Uh it might be really
expensive to buy certain products if you
live in another country. So you just
don't buy those products. But here in
the US, it's usually pretty cheap to
have things delivered. So, it makes it
seem like we have more variety because
we can choose from all these different
products and we don't have to pay a ton
of money for shipping, right? So, it
also makes it feel like there's more
variety. Uh also with restaurants for
example um when people uh want to go out
to eat here they usually say what do you
feel like today? Do you feel like
Chinese, Mexican, Thai, Mediterranean,
etc. They uh often um give options of
other countries cuisines. That's super
common here because we have a huge
variety of different cuisines from all
over the world. Of course, in other
countries, you have this too, but it's a
very very wide variety here. like just
in my city I can go eat food from
Bangladesh, from Nepal, from wherever.
Countries where many people have never
even tried their food before. Uh it's uh
really cool to have all of this variety
when it comes to restaurants. So those
were some of the unique things that I
wanted to mention. Uh maybe in the
future I'll do another video and talk
about some other elements, other unique
elements in the US. But I hope you
enjoyed this video. Remember that if you
want my pronunciation training, click on
the link below to sign up and you can
start to improve your pronunciation
skills in English. So check that out.
And thank you all for listening and
watching this video.